Mss.Rec.68 Mss.Rec.68
American Philosophical Society
- Audio recordings
  - Martha's Father's Uncle's Sleep Doctor Song, 1968-07-31; 12-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:15; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - Old Ewan's Sleep Doctor Song, 1968-07-31; 12-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:43; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - Song Refusing an Old Man (Skookum John), 1968-07-31; 12-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:54; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - Song Refusing an Old Man, 1968-07-31; 12-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:30; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - Martha's Autobiography: Her Experience Becoming a Sleep Doctor, 1968-07-31; 12-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:07; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
    Includes a song, probably Tlingit, which she heard in a dream.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Autobiography; Copper Center (Alaska); Shamanism--Alaska
  - Up-the-Line Dancing Song, 1968-07-31; 12-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:11; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - Up-the-Line Song (prior to 1905), 1968-08-10; 12-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:05; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tanacross language
  - Up-the-Line Song (prior to 1900), 1968-08-10; 12-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:01; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Up-the-Line Song, 1968-08-10; 12-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:49; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Up-the-Line Song, 1968-08-10; 12-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:47; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Up-the-Line Song, 1968-08-10; 12-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:48; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Up-the-Line Song, 1968-08-10; 12-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:50; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Up-the-Line Song, 1968-08-10; 12-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:45; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
  - 'E li ye, by Andy Brown, 1968-08-10; 12-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:08; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Snatch of Sleep Doctor's Song, 1968-08-10; 12-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:19; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Northway Song, 1907, 1968-08-10; 12-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:09; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Upper Tanana language
  - Tlingit Song, 1968-08-10; 12-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:47; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Yakutat Song, to Tcicqedi-yAtxi (1930), 1968-08-10; 12-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:35; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Tlingit Song with reference to GUnana (1916-1917), 1968-08-10; 12-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:29; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Andy Brown's Sorry Song for hs Uncle, Lower Tonsina, 1948, 1968-08-10; 12-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:45; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Jim McKinley's Sorry Song for his Cousin, Charles Otegay, 1968-08-10; 12-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:14; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
    Song was composed in 1919.
  - Ring Charley's Sorry Song for his Brother, Chitina, 1968-08-10; 12-25; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:40; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Oscar Ewan's Sorry Song for his son, Gulkana 1964, 1968-07-28; 13-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:02; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; Ewan, Pete
  - Fred Ewan's Sorry Song for his Mother's Brother (cousin), Gulkana, 1968-07-28; 13-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:48; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; Ewan, Pete
  - Kenny Lake, (i.e. Willow Creek) George's Doctor Song, 1968-07-28; 13-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:44; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; Ewan, Pete
  - Skookum John's Doctor Song about God, 1968-07-28; 13-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:31; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie
  - Big Stickwan's Sleep Doctor Song, 1968-07-28; 13-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:59; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie
  - Mrs. Lazy Charley's Sorry Song for her husband, 1968-07-28; 13-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:59; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie
  - Alice Craig's Sorry Song for her husband, 1934, 1968-07-28; 13-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:22; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie
  - Down-the-Line Dance Song, 1968-07-28; 13-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:15; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; Ewan, Pete
  - Down-the-Line Dance Song, 1968-07-28; 13-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:51; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; Ewan, Pete
  - Down-the-Line Dance Song, 1968-07-28; 13-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:16; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; Ewan, Pete
  - Names of the Months, 1968-07-28; 13-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:02; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie
    Ahtena language--Glossaries, vocabularies, etc.; Copper Center (Alaska); Months
  - Blind Sourdough Gene's Chicken Song, 1920?, 1968-08-08; 13-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:42; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
    Explanation of song given by Nancy George.
  - Just drumming, 1968-08-08; 13-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:35; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - Two love songs, 1968-08-08; 13-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:55; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - Double-beat song: "ai ye ho", 1968-08-08; 13-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:15; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - Nenana potlatch song: "a a hiye ho ho hiye", 1968-08-08; 13-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:19; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Potlatch--Alaska; Tanana language
  - Copper River, down the line song "iye...he he 'eye", 1968-08-08; 13-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:10; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - Ruth John's Mother's Love Song for Jim McKinley, 1968-08-08; 13-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:46; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - Tenas Charley's Aunt's Love Song, 1968-08-08; 13-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:09; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - Andy Wood's Love Song, 1968-08-08; 13-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:08; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - Camp Robber's (Canada Jay) song for Moose Hunting, 1968-08-08; 13-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:37; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - Chief Andrew's Love Song, 1968-08-08; 13-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:15; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
    Song is played twice.
  - Four stories told by Tenas Charley, 1968-07-30; 14-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:21; Charley, Tenas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
    Ahtena Indians--Folklore; Ahtena language; Bears--Folklore; Copper Center (Alaska)
  - Story of Man who married a Bear, 1968-07-30; 14-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:00; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta
    Ahtena Indians--Folklore; Bears--Folklore; Copper Center (Alaska)
  - Story of Kilya who married Bears, 1968-07-30; 14-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:55; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta
  - Jim McKinley's Sorry Song for Agnes's Mother, first attempt, 1968-08-03; 15-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:05; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McKinley, Jim
    Beginning of recording was originally recorded at higher speed, causing slower speed on playback. This problem has been digitally corrected, though some sound distortion remains in the opening :48. Song was re-recorded. See Related Recording.
  - Jim McKinley's Sorry Song for Agnes's Mother, Lower Tonsina 1924, second attempt, 1968-08-03; 15-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:12; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McKinley, Jim
    Re-recording of song. See Related Recording.
  - Jim McKinley's Sorry Song for Oscar Craig, 1967, 1968-08-03; 15-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:42; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McKinley, Jim
  - Jim McKinley's speech at potlatch for Oscar Craig, 1967, 1968-08-03; 15-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:32; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McKinley, Jim
    Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Mourning customs--United States--Alaska; Potlatch--Alaska; Speeches, addresses, etc.
  - Identification of recording, 1968-08-03; 15-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:25; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
    Identificaton of previously recorded items on reel. (APSdigrec_1478 - APSdigrec_1481)
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska
  - Martha Jackson's Mother's Father's Sorry Song for his Daughter, 1968-08-05; 15-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:34; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - Martha's "Grandpa" (Mother's Mother's Brother's) Sorry Song for his Brother, 1968-08-05; 15-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:28; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - Sorry Song by Martha's "Grandpa" (Mother's Mother's Brother), 1968-08-05; 15-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:37; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - Salmon Boy, 1968-08-08; 16-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:11; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie
    Ahtena Indians--Folklore; Copper Center (Alaska); Salmon--Folklore
  - Sarani Gai creation myths [1 of 2], 1968-08-08; 16-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:49; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; George, Bacille
    Ahtena Indians--Folklore; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Creation--Mythology; Raven (Legendary character)--Legends
  - Sarani Gai creation myths [2 of 2], 1968-08-08; 17-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:35; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Ewan, Annie; George, Bacille
  - Andy Brown's own Love Song for his cousin, 1968-08-15; 19-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:59; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
  - Joe Nicolai's Last Love Song (sung without fatal words), 1968-08-15; 19-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:21; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - Sorry Song for Johnny Frank of Tanacross, 1966, 1968-08-15; 19-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:26; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha
  - Mentasta Sam's Sorry Song for Mentasta Chief John, 1918 (his older brother), 1968-08-15; 19-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:39; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 1 of 24.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska; Potlatch--Alaska
  - Andy Wood's Sorry Song for his father after his mother's death, 1919, 1968-08-15; 19-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:24; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 2 of 24.
  - Chief Escaldita's Sorry Song for his Son, Chitina, 1915, 1968-08-15; 19-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:56; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 3 of 24.
  - John Ewan's (Fred Ewan's father) sorry song for his father, Gulkana, 1921, 1968-08-15; 19-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:32; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 4 of 24.
  - Ring Charley's Sorry Song for his Brother, 1918, Chitina, 1968-08-15; 19-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:25; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 5 of 24.
  - Chief John's Sorry Song for his Older Brother, 1912-1916 (?), 1968-08-15; 19-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:46; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 6 of 24.
  - Joe Goodlataw's Sorry Song for his Daughter (1962?), 1968-08-15; 19-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:11; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 7 of 24.
  - McKinley George's Sorry Song for His Daughter, 1925, 1968-08-15; 19-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:38; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 8 of 24.
  - Mrs. McKinley George's Sorry Song for her Daughter, 1925, 1968-08-15; 19-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:06; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 9 of 24.
  - Dancing Song and Jerkey Dance Song, 1968-08-15; 19-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:59; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 10 of 24.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Potlatch--Alaska
  - Jumping Dance Song, 1968-08-15; 19-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:45; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 11 of 24.
  - Andy Brown imitates calico tug-of-war, 1968-08-15; 19-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:55; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 12 of 24.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Potlatch--Alaska; Tug of war (Game)
  - Jerky Dance Song, 1968-08-15; 19-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:38; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 13 of 24.
  - Dance Song, "qaqaqa", 1968-08-15; 19-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:58; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 14 of 24.
  - Tsimshian Walking Song (learned from Tlingit), 1968-08-15; 19-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:22; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 15 of 24.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Potlatch--Alaska; Tsimshian language
  - Tlingit Dance Song, learned from Northway, 1968-08-15; 19-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:27; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 16 of 24.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Potlatch--Alaska; Tlingit language
  - Tlingit Song (for Tcicqedi-yAtxi), 1968-08-15; 19-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:43; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 17 of 24.
  - Tlingit Song (for GInexqwan-yAtxi) "Rest Song", 1968-08-15; 19-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:35; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 18 of 24.
  - Down Below Dance Song, 1968-08-15; 19-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:59; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 19 of 24.
  - Tlingit "Rest Song" (for GInexqwan-yAtxi), 1968-08-15; 19-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:16; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 20 of 24.
  - Down-the-Line Dance Song "ga la 'aha", 1968-08-15; 19-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:02; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 21 of 24.
  - Dance Song: "a a hiye ya iye heya", 1968-08-15; 19-25; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:10; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 22 of 24.
  - Andrew Isaac's Sorry Song for Johnny Frank, 1968-08-15; 19-26; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:18; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 23 of 24.
  - Lucy Adam's Sorry Song for her Son, Tetlin; Good Night spoken by Andy Brown, 1968-08-15; 19-27; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:18; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Part of an imaginary potlatch held at Copper Center. Part 24 of 24.
  - Up-the-line Dance Song, 1968-08-15; 19-28; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:48; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - Canadian Indian double-beat Dance Song, 1968-08-15; 19-29; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:46; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - Titus John's Song about Drunks that act like Muskrats, 1968-08-15; 19-30; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:41; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - Swans Fly Over My House, 1968-08-15; 19-31; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:39; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - About Ghosts, 1968-08-17; 20-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:43; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille
    Ahtena Indians--Folklore; Copper Center (Alaska); Ghost stories
  - The story of Skull Man and the Story of the Wise and Foolish Sisters, 1968-08-17; 20-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:38:19; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
    The Story of the Wise and Foolish Sisters is told primarily in Ahtena.
    Ahtena Indians--Folklore; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Ghost stories; Sisters--Folklore
  - Chief Andrew's Sleep Doctor Song: "Rich woman comes into your house", 1968-08-17; 21-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:01; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
    Begins with introduction to recording session by Frederica de Laguna.
  - Paxon John Love Song, 1968-08-17; 21-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:42; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
    Paxon John may have also been known as McKinley John.
  - Chitina Charley's Sleep Doctor Song: "I fly back home alive", 1968-08-17; 21-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:59; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - McKinley George's Sleep Doctor Song (I): "In Heaven I have a place", 1968-08-17; 21-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:23; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - McKinley George's Sleep Doctor Song (II): "Far off SArani", 1968-08-17; 21-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:56; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - Bacile George tells part of the story and sings Owl's Song to Frighten Bad Children, 1968-08-17; 21-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:20; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - Love Song of Abandoned Girl: "Who makes your clothes like a rainbow?", 1968-08-17; 21-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:44; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - Bacile George's Father's (Willow Creek George's) Aunt's Song Rejecting Tom Nealy's Father: "Why don't you keep quiet?", 1968-08-17; 21-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:35; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - Doris Chales Mourning Song for her Husband, Dot Lake, 1968-08-17; 21-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:48; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - Tlingit Song: "ayu he ye hi", 1968-08-22; 22-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:47; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Tlingit Song: "ye he ha", 1968-08-22; 22-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:12; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
    Singing led by Martha Jackson.
  - Tlingit Song: "he he ie ye eya", 1968-08-22; 22-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:44; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Tlingit Song: "tci dei gu ba", 1968-08-22; 22-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:10; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Tlingit Song: "'ala hu heya", 1968-08-22; 22-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:48; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Na'hayi Indian Song, 1968-08-22; 22-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:02; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
    Song is identified as coming from the Yukon, though the language of song is unclear from collector documetation. Most likely Southern Tutchone, perhaps Han.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Southern Tutchone language
  - Up-the-Line Dance Song: "hi ye haha", 1968-08-22; 22-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:59; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Dance; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Dance Song from Moosehide Reservation, near Dawson: "hi ha ye", 1968-08-22; 22-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:17; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Copper Center (Alaska); Han language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Dance; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Song, probably from Chitina (Tlingit), 1968-08-22; 22-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:20; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Tlingit Sorry Song: "i yai ho yoho", 1968-08-22; 22-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:56; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
  - Song for Sushana Potlatch, by Bill Justin, Joe Justin and Jack John Justin's father, 1916 (happy song?), 1968-08-22; 22-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:42; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Potlatch--Alaska
  - Dance (?) Song for Potlatch at Batzulnitas, 1916-18?, 1968-08-22; 22-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:41; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha; Justin, Jack John; Pete, Elizabeth; Pete, Mentasta; Stanfield, Fanny